上集成长的烦恼.
Previously on Growing Pains.
麦琪:你上州立教师学院的事情怎么样了?
Maggie: So what happened to your State Teachers College?
迈克:我没去.
Mike: I'm not going.
杰森:这到底是怎么回事,迈克?
Jason: Exactly what's going on mike?
迈克:我说谎了.
Mike: I lied.
杰森:你需要同样的住房,
Jason: You want that same rent.
你需要同样的吃饭,那么你就需要学点什么.
You want the Sever meal deal, then you've got to study something.
你必须是个学生.
You've got to be a student.
迈克:你是说如果我不按照你说的去做,
Mike: So you're saying that if I don't do what you say,
你就让我搬出去?
you're making me move out?
杰森:迈克搬走了.他走了.他的车子,
Jason: Mike's moved out.He's gone.His car, his clothes, everything.
他的衣服,一切.他搬出去去演那愚蠢的戏了.
He moved out to do that stupid play.
迈克:我是一个没有地方住的演员.你能帮忙吗?
Mike: I'm an actor without a place to stay.Would you please cut me a break?
女服务生:出去.
Waitress: Get out.
开萝尔:这就是我.我一个哥伦比亚大学的学生,
Carol: here I am.A Columbia student who has to leave at seven a.m.
现在需要早上七点出发去赶十点的课.但是要是我住在纽约呢?不.
to make a ten o'clock class.But do I live in New York?No.
迈克:会这样.一个无名的无家可归的人给我一块钱.
Mike: It's come to this.An anonymous homeless man gives me a buck.
开萝尔:我觉得迈克做的最棒的事情就是从这里搬走.
Carol: You know the best thing Mike ever did was move away from here.
麦琪:哦,真的?
Maggie: Oh really.
开萝尔:是的.如果我有钱,我也会这么做.
Carol: Yeah.If I had the money, I'd do the same thing.
麦琪:这是一张空白支票.你想搬走?搬走.
Maggie: A blank cheque.You want to move?Move.
迈克:开萝尔,多么令人惊奇的一致呀.你在来纽约的路上,我正从那里回来.
Mike: Carol, Carol.What an amazing coincidence.Here you are on your way to New
York and here I am on my way back there
埃迪:你们把我的两个孙儿赶出家门,你们乐意了,你这个庸医?
Ed: Are you happy now that you've driven out two of my grand kids, you quack?
女服务生:三明治,炒鸡蛋,火腿,
Waitress: Cheeseburger, scrambled egg, side of ham, toast,
土司,三杯橙汁,和辣土豆条.
three orange juices, and chilly fries.
迈克:放这.
Mike: Right here.
女服务生:她什么都不需要?
Waitress: Nothing for her?
迈克:帐单.
Mike: The bill.
开萝尔:帐单.
Carol: No.
女服务生:想不付帐的话,
Waitress: Skip out on the bill,
你会发现你的脖子移位的.
and you will be smelling out of the side of your neck.
开萝尔:别担心.我有钱.我有很多钱.
Carol: Don't worry.I have money.I have lots of money.
迈克:我明白,我有很多东西教你独立生活.
Mike: I can see I've got lots to teach you about living on your own.
开萝尔:我犯了严重的错误.
Carol: I've made a horrible mistake.
我找不到地方住了.叛逆的时候很神气,
I don't know anything about finding a place to live.
现在我怎么办呢?
One great moment of rebellion, now what am I going to do?
迈克:把芥末递给我.
Mike: Pass the mustard.
开萝尔:我处在我人生的分水岭,
Carol: I am at the watershed moment of my life,
而你所能说的就是把芥末递给我.
and all you can say is pass the mustard.
迈克:还有调味番茄酱.开萝尔,你担心什么?我意思是说,当妈妈爸爸把你赶出去的时候,至少他们给你一张空白支票.
Mike: And the ketchup.Carol, what are you so upset about?I mean, at least
mum and dad gave you a blank cheque when they threw you out
开萝尔:更正一下.他们把你赶出来.
Carol: Correction.They threw you out.
我只是想证明自己已经独立.
I was just merely demonstrating my independence.
迈克:哦,我明白了,
Mike: Oh, I see,
你厌倦了在变态之间乘车来往,因此你决定搬进城市跟他们靠近点.
so you were so tired of commuting amongst these perverts that you decided
好主意,开萝尔.
to go to the city to be closer to them.Good plan Carol.
开萝尔:你说的对.我没有权利来这.一个拿着空白支票的傻瓜.
Carol: You're right.I have no right to be here.A fool with a blank cheque.
迈克:嘿,嘿,嘿.
Mike: Hey, hey hey.Alright.I've had just about enough of that talk young lady.
我已经受够了这样的谈话,小女人.
I am going to take you under my wing and show you the ropes,
我会把你放在我的翅膀下面,告诉你诀窍,哪怕花掉爸爸妈妈的最后一分钱.
even if it costs mum and dad every last cent that they have.
开萝尔:哦,明白了.你想用我的空白支票兑现.
Carol: Oh, I get it.You are trying to cash in on my blank cheque.
迈克:开萝尔,你伤了我的心.
Mike: Carol, you wound me.
开萝尔:谢谢,但是不谢.我跟路边的陌生人在一起都比你强.
Carol: Thanks, but no thanks.I'd be better off with some guy off the street.
男人:嗨,你的女人给我,我付给你三十六美金.
Man: Hey, I'll give you thirty-six dollars for your woman.
迈克:哦,我喜欢.我喜欢.这还真是个好地方.
Mike: Oh, I like it.I like it.Alright this is the best place yet.
开萝尔:你还有比这更好点的吗?
Carol: Do you have anything a little nicer?
女人:有.我住着.
Lady: Yeah.I live in it.
开萝尔:景色真差.
Carol: This is one ugly view.
男人:嗨,宝贝.让我瞧瞧你跳舞.
Man: Hey baby.Let me see you dance.
女人:听好,我有几条规矩;没有毒品,
Lady: Now, I got few rules; no drugs, no cloven hoofed pets,
不准有养有分趾的宠物,不许放比吉斯音乐.
and no bee gees music.
迈克:啊,对不起.开萝尔,我都找累了.好啦.这地方要比其它地方好,你甚至有卧室.你可以放满书,你可以发疯,开萝尔.你可以每晚学习到深夜.
Mike: Ah, excuse us.Carol, I am tired of looking ok.This place is much
better than the other places and you can even have the bedroom.You can fill
it with books, you can go crazy Carol.You can study every night till midnight
开萝尔:有卧室,是吗?
Carol: There is a bedroom, right?
女人:穿过浴室,亲爱的.
Lady: Through the bathroom dear.Right passed the combination shower/toilet.
就穿过洗澡间兼厕所.迈克和开萝尔 西维尔,
Mike and Carol Seaver, you are in luck.
你们很幸运.我愿意把房子租给年轻的新婚夫妻.
I give preference to young married couples.
开萝尔:尽管不符合我的标准,我还是试试.
Carol: Against my better judgment, I'll give it a shot.But I get the bed.
但是我睡床.你的邋遢的女人我不欢迎,
None of your sleazy women are welcome,
如果你的朋友发现我,我就离开.
and even if one of your friends hits on me, I'm gone.
女人:我喜欢一个女人把自己的丈夫管牢.
Lady: I like a woman who keeps her husband on a short leash.
埃迪:空白支票!空白支票.你是不是从你的书里找到的鬼主意,小男人?
Ed: Blank cheque!Clank cheque.Did you get that bonehead move from one of your books, shrink man?
杰森:这不是我的鬼主意.是你女儿的.
Jason: It's not my bonehead move.It was your daughters.
麦琪:我说了,对不起.
Maggie: I said I was sorry.
埃迪:我什么也不会责怪你,除了你嫁给他.
Ed: I'm not blaming you for anything, other than marrying him.
杰森:对此,我不想回答你什么,
Jason: I'm not even going to respond to that Ed,
埃迪,
because I'm concentrating on what's important here.
因为我集中注意力考虑重要的事情.就是我们甚至不知道迈克和开萝尔在哪.
Which is that we don't even know where Mike and Carol are.
奶奶:百老汇94号.开萝尔打来的.我没有提到吗?
Grandma: Ninety forth on Broadway.Carol called.I didn't mention it?
麦琪:没有,你没有提到.她说什么了?
Maggie: No, you didn't mention it.What did she say?
奶奶:哦,我们谈的很好.
Grandma: Oh, we had a lovely chat.
谈话有点匆忙.
It was a little rushed, she had to go to Columbia.
她要去哥伦比亚.她一定对自己去南美洲很担心.
She must be really upset to go all the way to South America.
麦琪:是纽约的哥伦比亚大学,妈妈!
Maggie: It's Columbia University in New York mother!
埃迪:如果你还是对你妈妈大吼大叫,你可以走出这个家门.
Ed: You continue yelling at your mother like that and you can get out of our house.
麦琪:这是我的家.
Maggie: It's my house.
奶奶:我想你是对的.不是南美洲.
Grandma: I think you're right.It isn't South America.
埃迪:当然不是南美洲,笨蛋.
Ed: Of course its not South America ludnut.
奶奶:埃迪,记住,你大吼大叫的会胃气胀的.
Grandma: Now Ed, remember, when you yell you get flatulent.
埃迪:好,你使我难堪.
Ed: Nice, You've embarrassed me.
杰森:不是什么新闻,埃迪.
Jason: Not news Ed.
奶奶:你们没有理由这么担心.开萝尔很好.
Grandma: There's no reason to be this upset.Carol is fine.
她和迈克租了房子.
She's taken an apartment with Mike.
麦琪:迈克 西维尔!
Maggie: Mike Seaver!
奶奶:这个我也没有提及?
Grandma: I didn't mention that either?
麦琪:没有.我取我的钥匙.
Maggie: No.I'll get my keys.
杰森:等等,亲爱的,好好考虑一下.迈克和开萝尔同住.她会使得他的生活糟透的.他一两天就忍受不了开萝尔的疯狂.两个人会意识到他们犯下的大错误,然后两个都回家,就这样.
Jason: Wait honey, think about it.Mike and Carol room mates.She's going to make
his life miserable.He'll drive her crazy in a day or two.The both realize
the horrible mistake they've made and they'll both come home, like that
埃迪:哈!这种方法无效.
Ed: Ha!It never works that way.Look at poor Maggie here.
瞧瞧这可怜的麦琪.你们都结婚22年了,她还没回过家.
Twenty-two years since your wedding day and she still hasn't come home.
迈克:你和我谈话?
Mike: Are you talking to me?
男人:是呀.我拿到了新的剧本.我们把第二场作了修改.
Man: Ok.I got new pages.We have reworked act two.
迈克:你是谁?
Mike: Who are you?
男人:你的新导演.
Man: The new director.
迈克:之前的导演怎么回事?
Mike: What happened to the old director?
男人:他筹备的事情取消了.我们对第二场作了修改.
Man: His catering business took off.We have revised act two.
迈克:为什么?
Mike: Why?
男人:全是炮火.哦,我受不了.
Man: All that gunfire.Oh, it made me queasy.
迈克:我是牛仔.
Mike: I'm a cowboy.
男人:不是了.你是理发师.
Man: Not any more.You're a hairdresser.
开萝尔:这不是重复了吗?
Carol: But isn't that a tautology?
男孩:将你的无产阶级的观点与我分享.
Guy: Spare me your proletarian banality.
开萝尔:我想告诉你们,
Carol: I have got to tell you people how wonderful it is to be able to
将这些复杂的想法与别人分享是多么美妙呀.
share these complex thoughts with someone.
男孩:但是我想你是和你哥哥住在一起.
Guy: But I thought you lived with your brother.
开萝尔:对呀,但是和他在一起,我得说慢点,用单音节词.
Carol: I do, but with him I have to speak slowly and use one-syllable words.
男孩:对我就向教授一样.
Guy: As do I with certain professors.
开萝尔:哦,各位.这是我哥哥迈克.
Carol: Oh everyone.My brother Mike.
男孩:很高兴……见到你.
Guy: Nice....to ....meet...you.
迈克:开萝尔,我可以在厨房里和你私下谈谈吗?
Mike: carol, can I speak with you privately in the kitchen please?
瞧,我有许多台词要修改.我需要我的房间.
Look I've got lots of lines to revise.I need my apartment.
开萝尔:你的房间?
Carol: Your apartment?
迈克:是的,好了,开萝尔.我付两个月的租金.
Mike: Yes, come on Carol.I am paying the even months rent.
开萝尔:我可以提醒你,我慷慨你这个月才能住这里的.
Carol: may I remind you that you're staying this month out of my generosity?
迈克:是的.我也提醒你,你让我恶心.
Mike: Yeah well need I remind you that you make me puke?
男孩:打断一下.我们将讨论小组改在沙利文酒店.加入我们吧.
Guy: Pardon me.We are moving the discussion group down to Sullivan's pub.Join us.
开萝尔:不,我想我不能参加.我妈妈和爸爸……我能,我为什么不能呢?
Carol: No, I don't think I can.My mum and dad...I can, cant I?
好吧,但是我得八点之前回来,这样我有学习的时间.
Ok, but I have to be back by eight because I have hours of studying.
男孩:是不是凯克加特说的" 畏惧是一种同情心的反感"?
Guy: Wasn't it Keikergart who said, "Dread is a sympathetic antipathy"?
迈克:你鼻子有东西挂下来了.
Mike: You've got something hanging out of your nose.
麦琪:我希望我父母不管这些事情.他们怎么不回家呢?
Maggie: I wish my parents would stay out of this.Why don't they just go home?
杰森:或者让他们搬去加州,只是逢闰年来一次.
Jason: Or move to California and just visit leap years.
埃迪:你知道,如果开萝尔和迈克是我的孩子,
Ed: You know if Carol and Mike were my kids,
我就开车去纽约,抓住他们的脖子逮回来,
I'd drive down to the city and grab them both by the scruff of the neck,
塞在货车的后面,带回家,把他们锁在地下室,
shove em in the back of the van, bring them home,
不给饭吃,直到他们明白为止.
lock them in the basement without any food until they wised up.
奶奶:那是因为你是位亲切的父亲.
Grandma: That's because you are a loving father.
麦琪:你知道,我有点想去纽约,抓住他们的脖子逮回来,
Maggie: You know, part of me want to go down there,
塞在货车的后面,带回家,
grab them by the scruff of the next, shove them in the trunk of the car,
把他们锁在地下室,不给饭吃,直到他们明白.
drag them back home, look them in the basement until they wise up.
杰森:我敢打赌,你这种想法一定从老东西那里得来的.
Jason: I bet you got that from old chrome dome in there.
埃迪:重新回忆起来,凯特.
Ed: Refresh my memory Kate.
当年麦琪结婚的时候,我为什么不那样做呢,
Why didn't I do that with Mags when she married, uh, what's his name?
叫什么名字来着?老式发型的那个.
Old hairdo in there.
奶奶:你想要的很多,
Grandma: As much as you wanted to,
你意识到你不能控制你孩子的生活.
you realized that you couldn't control your child's life.
埃迪:是的,我忘记了.
Ed: Yeah, I forgot.
杰森:我想我们做的对.我们要坚持住,
Jason: I think we took the right course of action.
直到他们按照我们的思路回家.
We have to stand firm until they come home on our terms.
麦琪:你是对的.你是对的.我确信你是对的.
Maggie: You're right.I know you're right.I'm positive you're right.
杰森:谢谢.
Jason: Thank you.
麦琪:如果你错了的话,我们怎么办?
Maggie: So what do we do when you're wrong?
迈克:都凌晨三点了.她死哪里去了?(开萝尔进来)开萝尔,你去哪了?我都担心死了.我去了镇上的每个图书馆.
Mike: Its three am.Where the heck is she?(Carol comes in) Carol, where have
you been?I've been worried sick.I mean I called every library in town
开萝尔:你能感觉到了?你能听到了?你能闻到?你能尝到?
Carol: Can you feel it?Can you hear it?Can you smell it?Can you taste it?
迈克:什么?
Mike: Hu?
开萝尔:我调情.我跳舞.
Carol: I flirted.I danced.I had double cappuccinos and I laughed.
我喝了双份热牛奶咖啡,我还笑.我笑的多疯狂.
God how I laughed.
迈克:你不会跳下去吧,不会吧?
Mike: You're not going to jump are you?
开萝尔:我赢得的并不是乘车问题.我真正渴望的是自由.
Carol: My wining wasn't about the commute.
我离家的那个夜晚,祝福的液体流淌了我的全身,流进了我真正的灵魂.
What I really thirsted for was freedom.The
night I left, that blessed liquid flowed over me.Coursing its way to my very
soul
迈克:嗨,听着,
Mike: Hey listen; if you're not going to make nay sense,
如果你不反对的话,我就占用卧室了.
then I'll take the bedroom.
开萝尔:然后我将占有曼哈顿.嗨,自由女神!把那个火炬递给我.
Carol: Then I'll take Manhattan.Hey Miss Liberty!Hand me that torch.
麦琪:杰森!你为什么这么早就走?
Maggie: Jason!Why are you leaving so early?
杰森:哦,正在去办公室的路上,我想我还可以送衣服去干洗.
Jason: Oh, just on the way to the office, thought I'd drop off some laundry.
麦琪:对了.这火腿跟你的脏衣服有什么关系呢?
Maggie: Right.What's this ham doing with your dirty laundry?
杰森:那是因为我放进了本的三明治里面了?好了,
Jason: What did I put in bens sandwich? Alright Maggie, I admit it.
麦琪,我承认吧.我想给迈克和开萝尔包点吃的.
I'm packing some food for Mike and Carol.
麦琪:但是你说我们应该什么都不管,而且你如此确定.
Maggie: But you said we shouldn't do anything and you were so sure.
杰森:我是曾经确定,但是后来我开始想,
Jason: well I was sure, then I started thinking, how would your dad handle it.
换作你父亲该怎么处理呢.我和埃迪不同就在于我心肠软,
And what sets me apart from Ed is that I have a soft spot and I'm
我不怕承认这点.
not afraid to admit it.
但是我如果开始像他一样去做的话,我会被诅咒的.
And I'll be damned if I'm going to start acting like him.You're right.
你说的对.我们饿死他们.
Let them starve.
埃迪:我可以用你们的洗衣机吗?
Ed: May I use your washing machine.
麦琪:当然可以,爸爸.在地下室呢.
Maggie: Sure daddy.It's in the basement.
埃迪:谢谢.
Ed: Thank you.
克莉丝:妈妈.
Chrissy: Mummy.
麦琪:哎,小甜心.
Maggie: Yes sweetheart.
克莉丝:开萝尔还会搬回来住吗?
Chrissy: Will Carol ever move back?
麦琪:哦,亲爱的.是这样,
Maggie: Oh honey.Well carol just needs to work a few things out and we
开萝尔只是需要解决一些事情,我们只是给她一些空间,直到她回来.
just need to give her some space until she comes home.
克莉丝:这样的话,我该放弃卖掉她的衣服的打算?
Chrissy: So I should put off selling her clothes?
迈克:开萝尔.开萝尔,你干什么呢?都已经将近中午十二点了,而你,你还在我枕头上流口水.
Mike: Carol.Carol, what are you doing?It's almost twelve noon and you, you're drooling on my pillow.
开萝尔:滚开,迈克.
Carol: Go away Mike.
迈克:不是我想管你睡觉,但是你不是缺了101课了吗?
Mike: Not that I care, but aren't you missing geekology 101?
开萝尔:因此我睡过头.这是大事.
Carol: So I slept in late.Big deal.
迈克:你逃了一课.
Mike: You skipped a class!
开萝尔:我看到太阳亲吻天空.我是说人一生能这样几次?
Carol: \I watched the sun kiss the sky.I mean how often does a person get to do that?
迈克:每天.嘿,嘿,嘿,嘿.注意残渣.
Mike: Everyday.Hey hey hey hey.Watch the backwash.
开萝尔:轻松多了.
Carol: Lighten up.
迈克:哦,是吗?是.你一天都这样?
Mike: Oh, so that's it?That's it.That's you whole day?
开萝尔:值得讽刺的是,
Carol: And the ironic thing is that I've done more in these thirty seconds
我在这三十秒里做的事情比你一生要做的事情还要多.
than you'll do in your entire life.
迈克:我现在才明白那时侯我真应该三十六块钱把你卖掉.
Mike: You know I should have sold you for thirty-six bucks when I had
the chance.
迈克:没人,没人.唉,提词.
Mike: Nobody, nobody.Uh line.
男人:你应该记住台词.
Man: You were supposed to have this memorized.
迈克:你应该记住台词.
Mike: You were supposed to have this memorized.
男人:你记住什么了?
Man: Do you have anything memorized?
迈克:对不起.我现在跟我妹妹住在一起,她让我发疯.
Mike: I'm sorry.I've been living with my sister and she's driving me crazy.
男人:哦,不,不,不,不.我不管这个.我已经跟我妹妹生活了三十五年了,她从来不给我制造麻烦.
Man: Oh no, no, no, no.I don't buy that.I have been living with
my sister for thirty-five years, and she has never been a problem
迈克:好吧.我下午把这些素材记住.
Mike: Alright, I'll have this stuff memorized by the afternoon.
男人:不,不仅仅是这些台词.
Man: No, it's not just the lines.
对于你拿你妹妹作为借口,我的确不想揭穿.
And I certainly don't want to pierce your cover story about your sister.
迈克:你说什么?
Mike: What are you saying?
男人:我说把你的枪套和热辣的衣服放进柜子里.
Man: I am saying get your holster and hot rollers to wardrobe.
你已经放弃了最后一次机会.
You have given your final rinse.
迈克:开萝尔.开萝尔!怎么回事呀?这些是什么人?
Mike: Carol.Carol!What the heck is going on?Who are these people?
开萝尔:我今天见了他们所有人.他们是小人物?
Carol: I met them all today.Aren't they great?
女房东:他们是警察.
Landlady: there they are officer.
警察:好了,伙计.我们没有听太多的比吉斯音乐吗?走,都出去.
Policeman: Alright people.Haven't we had enough of that bee gees music?Let's go, everybody out.
女房东:你和你的放荡的妻子被驱逐了,小伙子.
Landlady: You and your swinging wife are evicted pal.
迈克:她是我妹妹.
Mike: She's my sister.
女房东:真恶心.
Landlady: that is really sick.
迈克:干的漂亮,开萝尔.真是干的漂亮.
Mike: This is great Carol.This is really great.
开萝尔:你对我发火?如果这样,你应该对他们发火.是他们的错.
Carol: You're getting mad at me?If anything you should be getting mad at them.They are the man.
迈克:你看看,你逃课,你睡懒觉到中午.你让这些液体流遍全身.你举办这些疯狂的舞会,你看着太阳亲吻天空,而且现在你让我们被驱逐.
Mike: Look, you cut classes, you sleep in till noon.You let these fluorides flow over you.You hold these wild parties, you watch the sun kiss the sky, and now you get us evicted.
开萝尔:迈克,我还认为所有人中你会理解我.
Carol: Mike, I thought you of all people would understand.
迈克:理解!开萝尔,你不能像那些漫无目的的少年鬼混!
Mike: Understand!Carol, you can't just drift along like some aimless teenage.
开萝尔:听听你自己.你知道你的口吻像谁吗?
Carol: Listen to yourself.Do you know what you sound like?
迈克:是的,我知道,
Mike: Yeah I do Carol.
开萝尔.我的口吻像有点责任心的人.
I sound like a guy who's got some sense of a little responsibility.
你知道,还像某个关心你的,但是你还没有明白的人……上帝,
You know and someone who cares about you even if you don't have the sense
我的口吻像爸爸.哦,
to see....god I sound like dad.Oh, Carol.I snapped.
开萝尔.我没有理由活下去了.
I have no reason to live.
开萝尔:让我给你弄点莲藕汁.
Carol: Let me get you some lotus root soup.
迈克:开萝尔,我怎么了?
Mike: Carol, what's happened to me?
开萝尔:最近演戏,你的压力太大.
Carol: You've just been under a lot of pressure lately with the play.
迈克:不,没有压力了.我今天被炒鱿鱼了.
Mike: No, the pressure's off.I got fired today.
开萝尔:哦,好呀,
Carol: Oh.Well Mike, look on the bright side.
迈克,你得看到好的一面.现在你有时间和我一起学习.
Now you have time to evolve into what I've become.
迈克:不,不,谢谢,开萝尔.我想挺直腰杆走.
Mike: No, no thanks Carol.I prefer walking erect.
开萝尔:尼采说过"不能打垮我们的就能使我们更强".
Carol: Nietze says "That which does not destroy us makes us stronger".
迈克:是呀,肯尼 洛杰斯也说过,
Mike: Yeah, well Kenny Rogers says you've got to know when to hold them
你需要知道什么时候伸,什么时候曲.
and know when to fold them.
麦琪:杰森.我刚接到我父亲的一个奇怪的电话.
Maggie: Jason.I just got the strangest call from my father.
他说什么地方都不要去,我们的问题解决了.你在干什么呢?
He said don't go anywhere, all our problems are over.What are you doing?
杰森:我去某个地方.随便什么地方.
Jason: I'm going somewhere.Anywhere.
麦琪:杰森,你可以给我父亲一个机会.
Maggie: Jason, you could give my dad a chance.
毕竟你的计划还没有出现效果.
After all your plan hasn't exactly worked like gangbusters.
迈克:是的,有效果.
Mike: Yeah it has.
麦琪:迈克,你在家.
Maggie: Mike, you're home.
迈克:我?
Mike: Am I?
杰森:这由你决定,迈克.如果你搬回来,你知道我们希望你干什么.
Jason: Well that's up to you Mike.You know what we expect of you if you are going to move back in here.
迈克:当然知道.我去那愚蠢的教师学院,待在那个学院直到我获得那无用的学位.
Mike: Alright I'll go to the stupid teachers college and I'll stay in school until I get my crummy degree.
麦琪:哦,难道那不好吗?
Maggie: oh isn't that wonderful.
杰森:你怎么在这,迈克?
Jason: Well why are you here Mike?
迈克:这么说吧,
Mike: Well let's just say that New York did not go the way I thought it
纽约并不是我想象的那样.
would.
麦琪:从来就没那么好.那个城市是个污秽场所.
Maggie: It never does.That city is a cesspool.
杰森:这样我们还是你的后盾?
Jason: So we're just your back up?
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
杰森:不.我想知道我们处在什么位置.
Jason: No.I want to know where we stand here.
迈克:好吧,你想让我说些什么,
Mike: Alright, what do you want me to say dad?
爸爸?你想让我说你正确,我还没有准备好?
You want me to say that you were right and I wasn't ready?Well you were.
好,你对了.
I, I don't like being poor and I don't like living off Carol.
我,我不想穷混,
And I don't like not knowing if I'm going to work tomorrow and even if
我不喜欢靠开萝尔生活.我不想过不知道明天是否有工作,
I did who the director would be or what part I would play,
即使有工作却不知道导演会是谁,或者我会演什么角色,甚至我是否还有角色的日子.
or even if I was going to have a part.Look dad.
如果你让我卑躬屈膝,我就卑躬屈膝.
If you want me to grovel, I'll grovel.
杰森:欢迎回家,迈克.
Jason: Welcome home mike.
麦琪:哦,你回来我真高兴.我甚至不介意你身上的臭味.
Maggie: Oh, I'm so glad you're home.I don't even mind if you smell.
杰森:你知道我正关注波顿学院的课程,那里有个戏剧小组,
Jason: you know I was noticing in that Boynton catalogue,
叫波顿大学演出团.
that there's a little theatre group there called the Boynton College Players.
开萝尔:别推我!
Carol: Don't push me!
麦琪:开萝尔.
Maggie: Carol.
迈克:哦,等等,如果她回来,这个交易取消.我搬出去.
Mike: Oh wait, if she's back the deals off.I'm moving out.
开萝尔:你想怎么对我都行,但是这是我的城市.
Carol: You can do what you want to me but it's my city.
这永远都是我的城市.
It will always be my city.
杰森:这怎么回事?
Jason: What's going on here.
埃迪:我们在五十八号大街逮住她玩三张纸牌的游戏.
Ed: We caught her playing three card Monty on fifty Eighth Street.
开萝尔:我赢了.
Carol: I was winning.
埃迪:进自己的房间,小姐.
Ed: Go to your room young lady.
麦琪:爸爸.只有父母才可以叫小孩回房间.
Maggie: Dad.Only a parent can tell a child to go to her room.
埃迪:好呀.玛格丽特,去你的房间.
Ed: Fine.Margaret, go to your room then.
杰森:听好,埃迪,
Jason: Listen Ed, thank you for bringing our daughter home.We owe you one.
谢谢你能把我的女儿带回家.我欠你一次.现在出去.
Now get out.
埃迪:你相信吗,凯特?我们把他们的孩子从鬼门关拉回来,而你急于赶我们走.
Ed: Did you believe that Kate.We pull their child from the jaws of hell and then you give us the bum's rush!
奶奶:我们过的很开心.谢谢邀请我们.
Grandma: We had a wonderful time.Thank you for inviting us.
开萝尔:你们两个不要骗我了.我知道你们派了一伙人来抓我.
Carol: You two don't fool me.I know you sent the goon squad to come and get me.
杰森:开萝尔,打住.等会儿.我说,你回家我们很高兴,但是如果你不想待在家里.我们不会强迫你.你想走的话,走.
Jason: Carol, hold on.Wait a second.I mean we are glad to have you home, but if you don't want to stay, we're not going to force you.You want to go, go.
开萝尔:再见.哦,你有坐出租车的钱吗?
Carol: see you.Oh, do you happen to have a cab fare?
麦琪:没有.
Maggie: No.
开萝尔:很好.这样我就待在这,直到死.
Carol: Great.So I am stuck here until I dye.
麦琪:开萝尔,不管你怎么侮辱我们,
Maggie: Carol, no matter how much you insult us,
你不会得到另外一张空白支票.
you are not going to get another blank cheque.
开萝尔:这,我能至少试试吗?
Carol: well can I at least try?
杰森:我告诉你我们要做什么.
Jason: I'll tell you what we will do.
如果哥伦比亚大学有合适的宿舍,如果你感兴趣,
If a dorm becomes available at Columbia, if you're interested,
那样我会帮你搬出去.
that's when we'll help you out.
开萝尔:你想那样公平吗?
Carol: And you think that's fair?
麦琪:是,我认为公平.
Maggie: Yes.We do.
开萝尔:我本来想得到一张空白支票,但是我想这样我也能活.
Carol: well I'd prefer a blank cheque but I guess I can live with that.
明天早上我就看太阳亲吻天空.
Tomorrow morning I'm going to watch the sun kiss the sky.
杰森:现在我们四个孩子中的两个回来了.就满足她的要求吧.
Jason: Now we have two of our kids back.Part of her anyway.
麦琪:我想,作为他们的父母,不仅仅变的更难.
Maggie: I wonder if being their parents didn't just get harder.
奶奶:打断一下.埃迪想知道我们能不能拿走我们的行李?
Grandma: Excuse me.Ed wants to know if we can our luggage?
斯丁克:本,在你有独立房间后,你真的变了.
Stinky: Ben, you've really changed since you got a place of your own.
本:这可不仅仅是房间.这是娱乐活动的场所.
Ben: Well it's not just the place.It's the pre party excitement.
宝贝们随时会过来.
The babes will be here any minute.
斯丁克:宝,宝,宝,宝,宝,宝,宝贝?
Stinky: B, b, b, b, b, b, babes?
本:欢迎来到本的娱乐宫,甜心.
Ben: Welcome to Ben's palace of pleasure you sweet thing.
迈克:扁你了,蠢蛋.那个臭男人怎么了?哦,你一定带女孩子过来的.
Mike: Beat it you twerp.What happened to the stink man?Oh, you must have girls coming over.
本:是的,我计划一个小晚会.
Ben: Yeah, I was planning a little party.
迈克:没门,小混蛋.出去.
Mike: No way you little horn ball.You're out of here.
本:哦,帮帮忙了,迈克.我求你了.女孩子随时会过来.
Ben: Oh come on Mike.I'm begging you.The babes will be here any minute.
迈克:那么我们在谈什么?
Mike: So what are we talking here?
本:我给你洗车.每天洗,一周,一年,先生.
Ben: I wash your car.Every day for a week.For a year, Sir.
迈克:你可知道,本,回家真好.00:22:18,400
Mike: You know Bennie, its good to be home.